[{"CardId":9,"TopicName":"WK6: LINQ","Question":"What is LINQ?","Answer":"Stands for Language-Integrated Query is a uniform query syntax in C# and VB.NET to retrieve data from different sources and formats.","Used":true,"Success":[0,0,0,0,0.5],"AvgScore":0},{"CardId":10,"TopicName":"WK6: LINQ","Question":"Why is LINQ Important, what does it do?","Answer":"It is integrated in C# or VB, eliminating mismatch between programming languages and databases, gives single querying interface for different data sources.","Used":true,"Success":[0,0,0,0,0],"AvgScore":0},{"CardId":11,"TopicName":"WK6: LINQ","Question":"What are the parts of a LINQ Query?","Answer":"Data Source, Query, and Execution","Used":true,"Success":[0,0,0,0,0],"AvgScore":0},{"CardId":12,"TopicName":"WK6: LINQ","Question":"What is the difference between deferred execution and immediate execution?","Answer":"Deferred execution requires a foreach loop, immediate can be done with an aggregate function (Count, ToList(), ToArray())","Used":true,"Success":[0,0,0,0,0],"AvgScore":0},{"CardId":13,"TopicName":"WK6: LINQ","Question":"Method vs Query syntax?","Answer":"Query syntax and method syntax are semantically identical, but many people find query syntax simpler and easier to read. ","Used":true,"Success":[0,0,0,0,0],"AvgScore":0},{"CardId":14,"TopicName":"WK6: Delegates","Question":"What is a delegate?","Answer":"Delegate is a reference data type in C# that defines the method signature","Used":true,"Success":[0,0,0,0,0],"AvgScore":0},{"CardId":15,"TopicName":"WK6: Delegates","Question":"What can a delegate do?","Answer":"It is a way to pass functions as parameters. Can be used in various ways, such as event handling or callback functions","Used":true,"Success":[0,0,0,0,0],"AvgScore":0},{"CardId":16,"TopicName":"WK6: Delegates","Question":"How would you declare a delegate?","Answer":"Declare a delegate\\nDefine which kind of method signature is needed for your delegate EX. Public delegate void MyDelegate(string msg);","Used":true,"Success":[0,0,0,0,0],"AvgScore":0},{"CardId":17,"TopicName":"WK6: Delegates","Question":"How would you set the target method for a delegate?","Answer":"Create a method that matches your delegate\u0027s signature, and then assign it to your delegate, EX. MyDelegate del = (string msg) =\u003E Console.WriteLine(msg);","Used":true,"Success":[0,0,0,0,0],"AvgScore":0},{"CardId":18,"TopicName":"WK6: Delegates","Question":"How would you invoke a delegate?","Answer":"Either using Invoke() method or with () operator, like how you would call any other function.\\nEX. del.Invoke(\u0022Hello World!\u0022);\\nEX. del(\u0022Hello World!\u0022);","Used":true,"Success":[0,0,0,0,0],"AvgScore":0},{"CardId":19,"TopicName":"WK6: Delegates","Question":"Explain multicasting","Answer":"You can assign more than one methods to a delegate, use the addition assignment operator (\u002B=) to tack on additional methods","Used":true,"Success":[0,0,0,0,0],"AvgScore":0},{"CardId":20,"TopicName":"WK6: Delegates","Question":"List some built in delegates.","Answer":"Func, Action, Predicate, EventHandler","Used":true,"Success":[0,0,0,0,0],"AvgScore":0},{"CardId":21,"TopicName":"WK6: Delegates","Question":"Explain Func","Answer":"Func has 0 or more input parameters and 1 output parameters.","Used":true,"Success":[0,0,0,0,0],"AvgScore":0},{"CardId":22,"TopicName":"WK6: Delegates","Question":"Explain Action","Answer":"Action takes in 0 or more input and returns void. Use Action with methods that have side effects but does not return anything","Used":true,"Success":[0,0,0,0,0],"AvgScore":0},{"CardId":23,"TopicName":"WK6: Delegates","Question":"Explain Predicate","Answer":"Predicate is a delegate that takes in one argument and returns a Boolean value. Equivalent to Func\u003Cin T, out bool\u003E","Used":true,"Success":[0,0,0,0,0],"AvgScore":0},{"CardId":24,"TopicName":"WK6: Delegates","Question":"Explain EventHandler","Answer":"Represents the method that will handle an event when the event provides data.\\nIt is a special type of multicast delegate, Use these with event keyword instead of delegate\\nEx. Public event EventHandler\u003CEventArgs\u003E MyEvent","Used":true,"Success":[0,0,0,0,0],"AvgScore":0},{"CardId":25,"TopicName":"WK6: SOA","Question":"What is SOA?","Answer":"SOA stands for Service Oriented Architecture, Decoupling the logic that processes the data (aka your backend logic) from the logic that presents your data (aka your front end logic)","Used":true,"Success":[0,0,0,0,0],"AvgScore":0},{"CardId":26,"TopicName":"WK6: SOA","Question":"What are the SOA principles?","Answer":"Standardized Service Contract, Loose Coupling, Service Abstraction, Service Reusability, Service Autonomy, Service Statelessness, Service Discoverability, Service Composability, Service Interoperability","Used":true,"Success":[0,0,0,0,0],"AvgScore":0},{"CardId":27,"TopicName":"WK6: SOA","Question":"What are the advantages and disadvantages of SOA?","Answer":"SOA doesn\u0027t have a single point of failure and the client doesn\u0027t have to wait for a request to process all all services, but it is more complex to build and cost more to make","Used":true,"Success":[0,0,0,0,0],"AvgScore":0},{"CardId":28,"TopicName":"WK6: REST","Question":"What does REST stand for?","Answer":"Stands for REpresentational State Transfer","Used":true,"Success":[0,0,0,0,0],"AvgScore":0},{"CardId":29,"TopicName":"WK6: REST","Question":"What is REST?","Answer":"An architectural style to design your services ","Used":true,"Success":[0,0,0,0,0],"AvgScore":0},{"CardId":30,"TopicName":"WK6: REST","Question":"What are the guiding principles of REST?","Answer":"Client-Server\\nStateless\\nCacheable\\nUniform Interface\\nLayered System\\nCode on Demand","Used":true,"Success":[0,0,0,0,0],"AvgScore":0},{"CardId":31,"TopicName":"WK6: REST","Question":"Explain Uniform Interface","Answer":"Your service would have an interface defined by four interface constraints: \\nIdentification of resources\\nManipulation of resources through representations \\nSelf-descriptive messages\\nHypermedia as the engine of application state (HATEOAS)","Used":true,"Success":[0,0,0,0,0],"AvgScore":0},{"CardId":32,"TopicName":"WK6: REST","Question":"Explain the Client Server Principle","Answer":"The client app must evolve separately from the server app without any dependency on each other\\nDecoupling your services from each other\\nServices should be independent from each other, even if they call upon each other","Used":true,"Success":[0,0,0,0,0],"AvgScore":0},{"CardId":33,"TopicName":"WK6: REST","Question":"Explain the Layered System Principle","Answer":"Constraining the interactions of your components to the ones in the next layer, such as the UI cannot access the DL services","Used":true,"Success":[0,0,0,0,0],"AvgScore":0},{"CardId":34,"TopicName":"WK6: REST","Question":"Explain Stateless","Answer":"Server isn\u0027t responsible for storing client state\\nThe server will not store anything about the latest HTTP request the client made\\nIt will treat every request as new\\nNo session, no history","Used":true,"Success":[0,0,0,0,0],"AvgScore":0},{"CardId":35,"TopicName":"WK6: REST","Question":"Explain Cacheable","Answer":"Resources from the server can be cached if applicable, these resources themselves must declare themselves cacheable\\nExample of a cacheable request: Get requests\\nExample of a non cacheable requests: Delete requests","Used":true,"Success":[0,0,0,0,0],"AvgScore":0},{"CardId":36,"TopicName":"WK6: REST","Question":"Explain code on demand","Answer":"Allows client functionality to be extended by downloading and executing code in the form of applets or scripts\\nWe usually send out static resources in the form of JSON or XML, but for example, the server can send executable script on the client side to render a part of the UI ","Used":true,"Success":[0,0,0,0,0],"AvgScore":0},{"CardId":37,"TopicName":"WK6: REST","Question":"Explain the Richardson Maturity Model","Answer":"A way to describe how REST compliant your service is\\nGrades your API according to the constraints of REST according to levels\\nLevel 0: Uses HTTP, single URI, one method (usually post)\\nLevel 1: Uses HTTP, multiple URIs, still one method (POST), Unique URI for each unique resource\\nLevel 2: Uses HTTP, multiple URIs, various http methods, Operations depend on the action method used\\nLevel 3: Uses HTTP, multiple URIs, various http methods, and HATEOAS","Used":true,"Success":[0,0,0,0,0],"AvgScore":0},{"CardId":38,"TopicName":"WK6: HTTP Request Lifecycle","Question":"Explain HTTP Request","Answer":"Send from client to server, 3 Parts\\nStart Line: Method - describes action to be performed, Target - describes where to send the request\\nHeader: Meta Data, Ex: content type - what data type the body has\\nBody: Data you want the server to process","Used":false,"Success":[0,0,0,0,0],"AvgScore":0},{"CardId":39,"TopicName":"WK6: HTTP Request Lifecycle","Question":"Explain HTTP Response","Answer":"From server to client, 3 Parts\\nStatus Line: Contains HTTP status codes of describing what happened when interacting with the server\\nHeaders\\nBody","Used":false,"Success":[0,0,0,0,0],"AvgScore":0},{"CardId":40,"TopicName":"WK6: HTTP Request Lifecycle","Question":"What are HTTP Methods?","Answer":"Describes what action the client wants the server to perform on a given resource\\nGET: Get resource\\nPOST: Create new resource\\nPUT: Update resource\\nDELETE: Delete resource\\nHEAD: Returns just the headers of a get response","Used":false,"Success":[0,0,0,0,0],"AvgScore":0},{"CardId":41,"TopicName":"WK6: HTTP Request Lifecycle","Question":"What is a safe method?","Answer":"A method is said to be safe if it does not change the state of the resource, GET, HEAD","Used":false,"Success":[0,0,0,0,0],"AvgScore":0},{"CardId":42,"TopicName":"WK6: HTTP Request Lifecycle","Question":"What is an Idempotent method?","Answer":"A method is said to be idempotent if the state of the resource is only affected once by any changes implemented by this method, DELETE, PUT, HEAD, GET","Used":false,"Success":[0,0,0,0,0],"AvgScore":0},{"CardId":43,"TopicName":"WK6: HTTP Request Lifecycle","Question":"How are status codes grouped?","Answer":"1XX informational (Mkay)\\n2XX communicating success (Success)\\n3XX redirection (We moved that)\\n4XX errors that are the client\u0027s fault, client side errors (your fault)\\n5XX errors that are the server\u0027s fault, server side errors (my bad)","Used":false,"Success":[0,0,0,0,0],"AvgScore":0},{"CardId":44,"TopicName":"WK6: HTTP Request Lifecycle","Question":"What is DNS?","Answer":"The Domain Name System (DNS) is the phonebook of the Internet. DNS translates domain names to IP addresses so browsers can load Internet resources.","Used":false,"Success":[0,0,0,0,0],"AvgScore":0},{"CardId":45,"TopicName":"WK6: ASP.NET","Question":"Explain the MVC Lifecycle?","Answer":"Request \u003E Routing \u003E Controller Initialization \u003E Action Execution \u003E Result Execution \u003E View Engine and Other ActionResult \u003E Result Execution \u003E Response","Used":true,"Success":[0,0,0,0,0],"AvgScore":0},{"CardId":46,"TopicName":"WK6: ASP.NET","Question":"What are some different kinds of filters?","Answer":"Authorization, Resource, Action, Exception, Result","Used":true,"Success":[0,0,0,0,0],"AvgScore":0},{"CardId":47,"TopicName":"WK6: ASP.NET","Question":"What is middleware?","Answer":"Middleware and filters are there to create a pipeline that short circuits/streamlines the processing of a client request","Used":true,"Success":[0,0,0,0,0],"AvgScore":0},{"CardId":48,"TopicName":"WK6: ASP.NET","Question":"What are some different ways to route?","Answer":"Default convention based routing and Attribute routing","Used":true,"Success":[0,0,0,0,0],"AvgScore":0},{"CardId":49,"TopicName":"WK6: ASP.NET","Question":"Explain Integration Testing","Answer":"Testing how multiple units work together\\nTakes longer than unit tests as there is a lot of overhead (since you are testing multiple components)\\nExternal components such as client requests and db responses are simulated ","Used":true,"Success":[0,0,0,0,0],"AvgScore":0},{"CardId":50,"TopicName":"WK6: Testing Doubles","Question":"What is Unit Testing?","Answer":"All about testing a single unit of code, usually a method, to make sure that it behaves as it should","Used":true,"Success":[0,0,0,0,0],"AvgScore":0},{"CardId":51,"TopicName":"WK6: Testing Doubles","Question":"Explain the test doubles","Answer":"Test doubles are a general term used to describe the dummy dependencies we set up for the unit test to utilize\\nMock\\nStubs\\nFakes","Used":true,"Success":[0,0,0,0,0],"AvgScore":0},{"CardId":52,"TopicName":"WK6: Testing Doubles","Question":"Explain Fakes","Answer":"Fakes are objects that have working implementations, but not same as production one. Usually they take some shortcut and have simplified version of production code.","Used":true,"Success":[0,0,0,0,0],"AvgScore":0},{"CardId":53,"TopicName":"WK6: Testing Doubles","Question":"Explain Mocks","Answer":"Mocks are objects that register calls they receive. In test assertion we can verify on Mocks that all expected actions were performed. ","Used":true,"Success":[0,0,0,0,0],"AvgScore":0},{"CardId":54,"TopicName":"WK6: Testing Doubles","Question":"Explain Stubs","Answer":"Stub is an object that holds predefined data and uses it to answer calls during tests. It is used when we cannot or do not want to involve objects that would answer with real data or have undesirable side effects. ","Used":true,"Success":[0,0,0,0,0],"AvgScore":0},{"CardId":55,"TopicName":"WK6: Testing Doubles","Question":"Explain Intergration Testing","Answer":"Testing how multiple units work together, Takes longer than unit tests as there is a lot of overhead\\nExternal components such as client requests and db responses are simulated ","Used":true,"Success":[0,0,0,0,0],"AvgScore":0},{"CardId":56,"TopicName":"DevOps Buzz Words","Question":"What is the cloud?","Answer":"A collection of servers owned by some service provider: AWS, Azure, GCP","Used":true,"Success":[0,0,0,0,0],"AvgScore":0},{"CardId":57,"TopicName":"DevOps Buzz Words","Question":"Explain Scaling","Answer":"Horizontal is adding instances of a service, vertical is upgrading the server your webapp runs on","Used":true,"Success":[0,0,0,0,0],"AvgScore":0},{"CardId":58,"TopicName":"DevOps Buzz Words","Question":"Explain the cloud service types","Answer":"Iaas Infrastructure as a service, PaaS Platforms as a service, SaaS Software as a Service","Used":true,"Success":[0,0,0,0,0],"AvgScore":0},{"CardId":59,"TopicName":"DevOps Buzz Words","Question":"What cloud deployment models are there?","Answer":"Private, Public, Hybrid and Community","Used":true,"Success":[0,0,0,0,0],"AvgScore":0},{"CardId":60,"TopicName":"DevOps Buzz Words","Question":"Explain DevOps","Answer":"a set of practices that allows us to roll out new features from the dev team and environment to production with quick response to any failures","Used":true,"Success":[0,0,0,0,0],"AvgScore":0},{"CardId":61,"TopicName":"DevOps Buzz Words","Question":"What does CI mean?","Answer":"Stands for Continuous Integration, Drives the ongoing merging and testing of code","Used":true,"Success":[0,0,0,0,0],"AvgScore":0},{"CardId":62,"TopicName":"DevOps Buzz Words","Question":"What does CD mean?","Answer":"Stands for either Continuous Deployment or Continuous Delivery, releasing code to production, deploy manual, delivery automated","Used":true,"Success":[0,0,0,0,0],"AvgScore":0},{"CardId":63,"TopicName":"DevOps Buzz Words","Question":"Explain what Docker does","Answer":"define a uniform environment in which our application runs on built with all the necessary configuration","Used":true,"Success":[0,0,0,0,0],"AvgScore":0},{"CardId":64,"TopicName":"DevOps Buzz Words","Question":"What is SDLC?","Answer":"A process used to design, develop and test high quality softwares, Plan\u003EDefine\u003EDesign\u003EBuild\u003ETest\u003EDeploy","Used":true,"Success":[0,0,0,0,0],"AvgScore":0},{"CardId":65,"TopicName":"DevOps Buzz Words","Question":"Explain Big Bang","Answer":"3 phases: Design? Build!!!! Test? Good for prototypes","Used":true,"Success":[0,0,0,0,0],"AvgScore":0},{"CardId":66,"TopicName":"DevOps Buzz Words","Question":"Explain Waterfall","Answer":"Rigid, Documented, You go through each phase once","Used":true,"Success":[0,0,0,0,0],"AvgScore":0},{"CardId":67,"TopicName":"DevOps Buzz Words","Question":"Explain V model","Answer":"the corresponding testing phase of the development phase is planned in parallel","Used":true,"Success":[0,0,0,0,0],"AvgScore":0},{"CardId":68,"TopicName":"DevOps Buzz Words","Question":"Explain Agile","Answer":"Agile is more of a concept, develop and deploy software quickly and being able to adopt to the changing client/business demands","Used":true,"Success":[0,0,0,0,0],"AvgScore":0},{"CardId":69,"TopicName":"DevOps Buzz Words","Question":"Explain Scrum","Answer":"Go through iterations, prepare shippable code at the end of each iteration","Used":true,"Success":[0,0,0,0,0],"AvgScore":0},{"CardId":70,"TopicName":"DevOps Buzz Words","Question":"Explain Backlog","Answer":"user stories that need to be implemented, have point value based on effort needed","Used":true,"Success":[0,0,0,0,0],"AvgScore":0},{"CardId":71,"TopicName":"DevOps Buzz Words","Question":"Explain Project Board","Answer":"How you keep track of the project during development, tracks what is to do, in progress etc.","Used":true,"Success":[0,0,0,0,0],"AvgScore":0},{"CardId":72,"TopicName":"DevOps Buzz Words","Question":"Explain a Burndown Chart","Answer":"used in sprint review to see the sprint\u0027s velocity, The velocity describes the total amount of points finished during sprint","Used":true,"Success":[0,0,0,0,0],"AvgScore":0},{"CardId":73,"TopicName":"DevOps Buzz Words","Question":"What is the difference between DevOps and Scrum?","Answer":"With DevOps, you deploy code in production at the end of each iteration (sprint), whereas with Scrum, your goal is to only prepare shippable code at the end of each iteration","Used":true,"Success":[0,0,0,0,0],"AvgScore":0}]